Welcome back. In this video,
欢迎回来 在本节视频课程
we'll talk a little bit about the independent component analysis algorithm.
我们将继续介绍独立成分分析算法
So, this is going to be a very high level view.
这轮讲解的内容比较笼统
We will not delve deep into the math.
我们不会深入研究数学层面的问题
We'll refer you to the right place but it's good and invaluable that you know,
而是会引导你朝正确的方向学习
just have a general idea about how it works and
了解该算法大致的运作原理
what assumptions are there when we want to use it.
以及使用时所需的假设 就很好很有价值了
And so, what we have,
那么 我们现在有什么呢？
the data set that we have we call X.
我们有一个名为 X 的数据集
And so that X was generated by multiplying what we would call it a mixing matrix,
该数据集是通过乘以混合矩阵生成的
which is A by the source signals,
混合矩阵也就是信源信号 A
which we also don't have.
我们也没有
So, we don't have A, we don't have S. But,
所以 我们没有 A 也没有 S
S is what we want to calculate in the end.
S 是我们最终想要计算得出的结果
And so, if X is A times S. We can say that S, which is the source.
所以 如果 X=A×S 我们可以说 S 为 信源
The goal of what you want here is W,
这里你想求得的是 W
which is the inverse of A.
也就是 A 的倒数
So, if A is the mixing matrix we can call W the unmixing
那么 如果 A 为混合矩阵 我们就可以称 W 为非混合矩阵
matrix times X, times a data set that we have.
W 为非混合矩阵× X 即乘以我们所有的某数据集
The original recordings that we have.
也就是我们的原录音
And so, this formula here.
那么在该公式中
So, X is an input that we have.
X 是我们所有的输入项
W is what we are trying to calculate.
需要计算得出 W
S is the result.
S 为结果
So, we ICA algorithm and process is all about approximating W or finding
所以 独立成分分析算法和其过程全部的目标是趋近 W
the best W that we can multiply by X the data set here to produce the original signals.
或者给出最佳的 W 以与 X 即该数据集相乘 来产生原始信号
The ICA algorithm is explained clearly in
名为《独立成分分析：算法与应用》的论文
this paper called the Independent Component Analysis: Algorithms and Applications.
对独立成分分析算法作出了清楚的解释
It goes into the derivation of everything here.
它衍生出了这里的所有事物
It shows a couple of ways to calculate a number of different parts of the algorithm.
也展示了该算法各部分的多种计算方法
But, if we're to have a just a very high level view of the algorithm,
但是如果我们只想宏观地学习一下这种算法
called FastICA. So, this is one way.
就可以使用固定点算法 这只是一种方法
This is the one that's implemented actually in scikit-learn.
实际上也应用在 scikit-learn 中
First, we have X,
首先 我们有 X
which is our data set.
这是我们的数据集
We will center it and whiten it.
我们将其居中 白化
And then, we will choose an initial random weight matrix,
然后 选择一个初始的随机权重矩阵
we'll call that W. And third step we
我们称之为 W 第三步
estimate W and W as a matrix contains vectors, a number of vectors.
我们对 W 做出预估 W 是包括多个向量的矩阵
Each one is as a weight vector.
每个向量都是权值向量
After we estimate it we decorrelate it and decorrelation is
预估后 我们进行去相关操作
to prevent W_1 and W_2 to sort of convert the same values.
即防止 W1 和 W2 转化为同样的值
So, we want them to convert to different values.
我们希望它们转化为不同的量
And then, we repeat from three until we convert,
然后 我们重复第三步 直到发生转换
until we find a value of W that we're satisfied with.
直到我们找到我们满意的 W 值
So, most of the math comes at step number three here.
所以 大部分数学运算都发生在第三步
And so, how does the estimation happen?
那么估算是如何进行的呢？
This is the sort of formula for estimating each of the vectors here.
这是用于估算每个向量的公式
Where E is the expected value,
E 是期望值
x is the data set,
x 是数据集
g is just some non-quadratic function.
g 为非二次函数
We have the ability to choose a number of them.
我们可以在常用公式
What is commonly used,
和 scikit-learn 所用公式中
what scikit-learn uses and what the paper proposes as one of the options is tanh.
选择多个公式 或是论文中提出的一个可选项 双曲正切
Hyper-tangent function.
正切函数
And the decorrelation is calculated like this.
去相关操作像这样计算
So, let's talk a little bit about it.
我们稍微谈一下
So, since it might seem a little bit cryptic.
因为它看起来有些神秘
So, ICA assumes a couple of things.
独立成分分析会提出若干假设
It assumes that the components are statistically independent and
它假设各成分是分别统计的
the paper explains a little bit what that means in statistical language.
该论文对分别统计在统计学语言中的含义稍做解释
And, it also assumes that components must have non-Gaussian distributions.
它也假设成分须为非高斯分布
And, non-Gaussianity is very important here.
非高斯分布在这里很重要
It's actually the key to estimating ICA and without it will not be able to calculate.
它是估算独立成分分析的关键 没有它就无法计算
We'll not be able to restore the original signals if they were Gaussian.
如果它们是高斯分布 我们就不能恢复原始信号
And so, building from here,
有基于此
the central limit theorem tells us that the distribution of a sum of
中心极限定理告诉我们
independent variables tends towards a Gaussian distribution.
一些自变量的分布趋向高斯分布
And so, knowing that we take W,
了解了这些 我们取 W
this weight matrix here.
这个权重矩阵
We take it to be a matrix that maximizes the non-Gaussianity of W transpose X.
将其作为 W 转置 X 时 实现非高斯分布最大化的矩阵
And so, non-Gaussianity strikes here again.
这样一来 非高斯性又将产生重要影响
But here, it's actually we have to calculate non-Gaussianity because
但是在这里 我们必须计算非高斯性
that's the term that this entire algorithm tries to maximize.
因为这是整个算法尝试将其最大化的项目
And so, what's one way to calculate non-Gaussianity?
那如何计算非高斯性呢？
This term here is an approximation of something called negentropy and negentropy
在这个案例中 该术语就相当于所谓的负熵
comes from information theory where the idea of entropy comes from.
负熵是信息理论的概念 该理论提出了信息熵的理念
And this is a way to sort of approximate it.
这是大致估计的一种方法
You don't need to know all these details as long as you know
你不必了解所有的细节 只要了解
the assumptions of non-Gaussianity.
非高斯性假设
That the independent components have to be independent.
独立成分必须是独立的即可
Or else, I say we will not be able to find them.
否则我们不可能发现它们
If you know these conditions and you know
了解这些条件
the situation where ICA needs to work, that's important.
以及独立成分分析运行的情境 是最重要的
If you want to know the details of and look at the derivation,
如果你想了解细节及其衍生理论
the paper is link in the-
可参阅链接中的论文